<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
     xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
     xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel>
  <title>(Interview RMoD #1: Damien Cassou)</title>
  <atom:link href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-damien.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
  <language>en</language>
  <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 22:04:47 +0100</pubDate>
  <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 22:04:47 +0100</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>Emacs 24.4 Org-mode 8.2.10</generator>
  <webMaster>nicolas@petton.fr (Nicolas Petton)</webMaster>
  <image>
    <url>http://nicolas-petton.fr/images/nicolas-petton.png</url>
    <title>(Interview RMoD #1: Damien Cassou)</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  </image>


  <item>
    <title>Interview with Damien Cassou</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-damien.html#sec-1</link>
    <author>Nicolas Petton</author>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-damien.html#sec-1</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 15:57:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <category><![CDATA[RMoD]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
    <description><![CDATA[
    <div class="pubdate">
    January 15, 2014
    </div>

    <p>
    <b>This is the first post of a series</b>, in which I <a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/working-at-rmod.html">interview my
    colleagues</a> of the <a href="http://rmod.lille.inria.fr/web/">RMoD</a> team (in Lille, France), with the hope that I
    can share part of what it really means to work here.
    </p>

    <p>
    Here&rsquo;s the interview of <a href="http://damiencassou.seasidehosting.st/">Damien Cassou</a>. Damien and I are in the same
    office, and we both share a passion for anything related to <a href="http://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a>,
    <a href="http://ubuntu.com">Ubuntu</a> and Smalltalk, which often leads to animated discussions and
    jokes with/from others.
    </p>

    <p>
    During the day, we listen to the same music, from one of our
    computers, and often go back to Atom Heart Mother when we don&rsquo;t
    agree on listening anything else.
    </p>


    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/damien-cassou.jpeg" alt="Damien Cassou image" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 1:</span> Damien at work</p>
    </div>


    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/pink-floyd-wall.jpeg" alt="A Pink Floyd image" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 2:</span> Pink Floyd poster on the wall</p>
    </div>

    <p>
    <b><i>Hi Damien, thanks for taking this interview.</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>First things first, could you tell me a bit about yourself?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    Hi Nicolas. I&rsquo;m 30 years old, I am married, and got a baby girl 10 months
    ago. I spent around 28 years in Bordeaux, France, where I did all my
    studies (from the first school at 3 to the PhD thesis at 28). Then I did a
    postdoc in Potsdam, Germany and one in Paris, France.
    </p>

    <p>
    I fell in love for computers when my father taught me how to program, I
    was 10. I never stopped: I read all the computer books I had and I
    learned a lot of programming languages before entering university. Then
    I got a master thesis, engineering degree, and PhD in computer science.
    I&rsquo;m now working as associate professor (maître de conférence) in RMoD
    and I couldn&rsquo;t have dreamed about a better job.
    </p>

    <p>
    When I&rsquo;m not at work, I take care of my wife (Jenny) and daughter
    (Sarah). I really like to walk in forests and mountains and I try to do
    that with them as often as I can (not often enough though). I also try
    to understand geopolitics, a topic I find deeply interesting.
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>Can you describe in a few lines what you work on at RMoD?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    As associate professor half of my time is for teaching and the rest
    (around half as well :-)) is for searching. By searching I mean advising
    students, (co-)writing papers (research articles, reports, books,
    project proposals, etc.), attending meetings, traveling, etc. 
    </p>

    <p>
    But what I really like is developing. Recently, I&rsquo;ve been working on
    <a href="http://www.smalltalkhub.com/#!/~Pier/Pillar">Pillar</a> and the <a href="http://www.smalltalkhub.com/#!/~Pharo/PharoLauncher">Pharo Launcher</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>You said that you couldn&rsquo;t dream of a better job. What is it that
    you like so much about it?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    I really like the team. I really like Pharo. I really like the topics
    covered by the team (modularisation and remodularisation). I really
    like teaching. I really like to have time to write software. I really
    like the chocolat au Daim :-).
    </p>

    <p>
    What I really like in RMoD is that we can closely collaborate with each
    other. Frequently, I would just sit with someone and start working with
    him or someone would come to my desk and work with me. 
    </p>

    <p>
    These pair-programming sessions are always a good time to learn a
    lot, have fun, and make huge progress. Pair-working also helps
    finishing tasks we don&rsquo;t want to work on.
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>How does your typical day at Inria look like?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    There is no typical day: all days are different and this is another
    aspect I like about the job. 
    </p>

    <p>
    Sometimes I will spend my day pair-programming (for example during
    one of our frequent sprints). Sometimes I will spend hours writing
    a paper or report with a colleague. Sometimes I will spend quite
    some time in meetings. Sometimes I will teach for many hours and
    arrive in the lab when most already left. Sometimes Anne would drop
    by and ask me thousands of questions :-). Too often JB will just
    enter the office and talk about random stuff for hours :-D. Each day
    is different and I like nearly all of them!
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>What question would you ask another member of the team?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    What would you change in the team to make it even more awesome?
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>Thank you again Damien!</i></b>
    </p>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    <script type="text/javascript">
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'nicolas-petton'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
    var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
    dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
    (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
    </script>
    <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
    <a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink">comments powered by <span class="logo-disqus">Disqus</span></a>
    ]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
