<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
     xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
     xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel>
  <title>Interview RMoD #4: Jean-Baptiste Arnaud</title>
  <atom:link href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-jean-baptiste.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
  <language>en</language>
  <pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 22:25:01 +0200</pubDate>
  <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2016 22:25:01 +0200</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>Emacs 25.1 Org-mode 8.3.5</generator>
  <webMaster>nicolas@petton.fr (Nicolas Petton)</webMaster>
  <image>
    <url>http://nicolas-petton.fr/images/nicolas-petton.png</url>
    <title>Interview RMoD #4: Jean-Baptiste Arnaud</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  </image>


  <item>
    <title>Interview with *Jean-Baptiste* Arnaud</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-jean-baptiste.html#orgheadline1</link>
    <author>nicolas@petton.fr (Nicolas Petton)</author>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-jean-baptiste.html#orgheadline1</guid>
    <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jun 2014 15:53:00 +0200</pubDate>

    <description><![CDATA[<div class="pubdate">
    June 11, 2014
    </div>

    <p>
    This is the fourth post of my series of interviews, in which I
    <a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/working-at-rmod.html#MissingReference">interview my colleagues</a> of the <a href="http://rmod.lille.inria.fr/web/">RMoD</a> team.
    </p>

    <p>
    Jean-Baptiste was already part of the team when I arrived, so as far
    as I'm concerned he's been there forever! He currently shares his
    office with Damien Pollet, two doors from mine. 
    </p>

    <p>
    He is a fun guy to work with, and he always has something to say
    about any topic, being work-related or not.
    </p>


    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/jb-1.jpeg" alt="Jean-Baptiste Arnaud image" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 1:</span> JB at work</p>
    </div>


    <p>
    <b><i>Hi Jean-Baptiste, thanks for taking this interview. Can you start
    by telling me a bit about yourself?</i></b>
    </p>


    <p>
    My name is Jean-Baptiste Arnaud, I'm 28 years old. I am in the Pharo
    community and in the RMoD team since 5 years. 
    </p>

    <p>
    Two years ago I finished a PhD in language design and security, and
    obviously all of the experiments were done using the Pharo image and
    virtual machine.
    </p>

    <p>
    I am now a Post-doc in the RmoD team, still working on different
    language projects.
    </p>

    <p>
    When I was young, I wanted to be an inventor. You know like Gyro
    Gearloose from "Duck Tales". Unfortunately high school do not offer
    this kind of career. I was always passionnate about "how" things
    work, this passion can probably explain my strange academic career:
    two years in Computer science, one year in biological science, two
    years in management (where I meet Stephane) and then my second
    master year in computer science with a focus on research. After
    that I started my PhD in the RMoD team.
    </p>

    <p>
    I am the annoying guy of the team, the guy talking too much (and I
    shared my office with the most silent guy of the team).
    </p>

    <p>
    On the personal side, I am a multi-passion kind of guy with a lot of
    short term passions and a couple of really long term ones.  I like
    books (art, RPG, comics and real book with only words in it), video
    games and obviously movies.
    </p>


    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/jb-2.jpg" alt="Raspberry" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 2:</span> Two of JB's toys</p>
    </div>

    <p>
    <b><i>What was your experience of the RMoD team as a PhD student?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    The first years, you enjoy it a lot: you have a lot to learn, to
    teach and you can have fun producing nice prototype :-).  It was
    also my first real experience in the scientific world, I wasn't
    really prepared to do a Phd. So it was a mix of bad and good
    surprises, but mostly good!
    </p>

    <p>
    The second year your try to produce papers, in my case that was a
    pain not from the ideas point of view but for the writing one. I am
    disorthographic so writing is not really my best skill. Except from
    that the second year was really cool for my research because I
    started to have enough knowledge and my research began to be
    mature.  
    </p>

    <p>
    And the Third year, well... I do not remember! At least the last 6
    months. Writing a PhD thesis is hard for everyone I think, and as
    every PhD student, I was disappointed not to be able to go deeper.
    </p>

    <p>
    But overall, It was a good experience, I learned a lot, and I like the
    spirit of the team.
    </p>

    <p>
    I will stay in the Rmod team for my post-doc. Put me back five years
    in the past and I would redo it, some aspects differently, but I
    woudld definitely redo It.
    </p>


    <p>
    <b><i>Stéphane had a question for the next interview: What would you like to invent?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    Good question! I will change it to <b>what you want to offer to the world?</b> 
    </p>

    <p>
    I think most of the people expected my silence. But, I will answer a
    "little helper" :-).
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>What question would you ask another member of the team?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    Only one ? Ok I will try: Would you like to small talk?
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>Thank you Jean-Baptiste!</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    If you liked this interview, you might also want to check out the
    <a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-stef.html#MissingReference">Interview with Stéphane Ducasse</a>.
    </p>


    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    <script type="text/javascript">
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'nicolas-petton'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
    var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
    dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
    (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
    </script>
    <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
    <a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink">comments powered by <span class="logo-disqus">Disqus</span></a>
    ]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
