<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
	 xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	 xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	 xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	 xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	 xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	 xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	 xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
     xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel>
  <title>(Interview RMoD #2: Esteban Lorenzano)</title>
  <atom:link href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-esteban.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
  <language>en</language>
  <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 10:06:02 +0100</pubDate>
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2014 10:06:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>Emacs 24.3 Org-mode 8.2.5h</generator>
  <webMaster>petton.nicolas@gmail.com (Nicolas Petton)</webMaster>
  <image>
	<url>http://nicolas-petton.fr/images/nicolas-petton.png</url>
	<title>(Interview RMoD #2: Esteban Lorenzano)</title>
	<link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  </image>

  <div id="table-of-contents">
	<h2>Table of Contents</h2>
	<div id="text-table-of-contents">
	  <ul>
		<li><a href="#sec-1">Interview with Esteban Lorenzano</a></li>
	  </ul>
	</div>
  </div>

  <item>
	<title>Interview with Esteban Lorenzano</title>
	<link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-esteban.html#sec-1</link>
	<author>Nicolas Petton</author>
	<guid isPermaLink="false">http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-esteban.html#sec-1</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2014 17:03:00 +0100</pubDate>
	<category><![CDATA[RMoD]]></category>
	<category><![CDATA[interview]]></category>
	<description><![CDATA[
	<div class="pubdate">
	<p>
	February 6, 2014
	</p>
	<i class="fa fa-calendar-o"></i>
	</div>

	<p>
	This is the second post of my series of interviews, in which I
	<a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/working-at-rmod.html">interview my colleagues</a> of the <a href="http://rmod.lille.inria.fr/web/">RMoD</a> team. After the <a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-damien.html">interview of
	Damien Cassou</a>, I interview <a href="http://smallworks.com.ar/web/blog">Esteban Lorenzano</a>.
	</p>

	<p>
	<a href="http://smallworks.com.ar/web/blog">Esteban</a> is one of the <a href="http://playingwithobjects.wordpress.com/">many</a> <a href="http://marianopeck.wordpress.com/">argentinians</a> who have been working at
	<a href="http://inria.fr">Inria</a>. Esteban joined <a href="http://rmod.lille.inria.fr">RMoD</a> almost at the same time as I did, two
	years ago. We since became very good friends, and often meet after
	work or during weekends, being for a beer <a href="http://www.cafecitoyen.org/">somewhere</a> in Lille or an
	evening sharing a dinner or simply talking, with other colleagues or
	friends.
	</p>

	<p>
	We also have a lot in common when it comes to work, and often work
	together on <a href="http://smalltalkhub.com/#!/~francois/MongoTalk">various</a> <a href="http://smalltalkhub.com/#!/~estebanlm/Voyage/">projects</a>. We are both passionate about
	Smalltalk, web development and databases.
	</p>


	<div class="figure">
	<p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/esteban1.jpg" alt="Esteban Lorenzano image" align="center" />
	</p>
	<p><span class="figure-number">Figure 1:</span> Esteban, focused and working hard as always</p>
	</div>

	<p>
	<b><i>Hi Esteban, thanks for taking this interview. Can you tell me a
	bit about yourself and how you joined RMoD?</i></b>
	</p>

	<p>
	Well, my name is Esteban Lorenzano and I&rsquo;m argentinian (one of the
	many argentinians in the Pharo community). I&rsquo;m 42 years old and I&rsquo;ve
	spent the biggest part of my life programming, since I saw a
	Commodore computer in a supermarket, when I was fourteen. 
	</p>

	<p>
	Watching people doing stuff with that computer was like seeing a
	wizard transforming the world, and that image cached me from that
	moment and forever. It was not always easy though, and I spent too
	many years programming in mainstream languages (I like some, I hate
	others) until I re-discovered my programmer vocation one day that I
	downloaded a Seaside image, &ldquo;just to have inspiration and fun, while
	working on really boring stuff&rdquo;... and the rest is history: I left
	my position as a &ldquo;senior architect&rdquo; and founded my own company
	<a href="http://smallworks.eu">smallworks.eu</a> with two friends to work on Pharo (very new at the
	moment) and Seaside, and I&rsquo;ve been contributing to Pharo since then,
	in different small projects.
	</p>

	<p>
	Then for different non work-related reasons, after two years me and
	my company became just one (my friends needed to switch to other
	projects) and I was also ending a relationship. Just at the same
	time Stef and Marcus proposed me to join the RMoD team as a Pharo
	engineer. It was perfect timing for me, and here I am, in the best
	job I have ever had.
	</p>

	<p>
	When I&rsquo;m not hacking something (at work or at my place), I have also
	a lot of different interests: I love to read, to write stories, to
	travel, to learn new stuff: I studied philosophy (yet not finished)
	and I try to be aware of the problems at my country and the world
	(and even try to help, when I see that I can do something). Last but
	not least, I love to spend time just hanging out with my friends.
	</p>


	<div class="figure">
	<p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/esteban2.jpg" alt="Mate image" align="center" />
	</p>
	<p><span class="figure-number">Figure 2:</span> Esteban&rsquo;s Mate</p>
	</div>

	<p>
	<b><i>Damien had a question for the next interview: What would you change
	in the team to make it even more awesome?</i></b>
	</p>

	<p>
	No clue :)
	</p>

	<p>
	I think as a team we have a lot of stimulus and excitment, but
	sometimes due the very nature of the team (which in fact is a
	research team), we have problems to get focus in the engineering
	part of Pharo: we are so excited about including new stuff or
	exploring some areas that we lose the need of committing to a task
	and not stopping until it is finished. If I had to improve
	something, it would be that part.
	</p>

	<p>
	<b><i>You are an Argentinian living in France for 2 years. Can you describe
	what it is to live in Lille? What does a typical week look like?</i></b>
	</p>

	<p>
	I could say that It’s quite challenging, but I would be lying :)
	</p>

	<p>
	The composition of the team is very international, and because of that
	the &ldquo;official language&rdquo; is english (oh, well... a weird dialect of it,
	the RMoD-English, which is like a combination of french, spanish, some
	german and english, everything in all kind of different and strong
	accents). But what is an advantage at work, and proved to be a problem
	for day-to-day life: I took too much time learning french (just now I
	can say I can handle a real conversation), and that prevented me from
	<b>really</b> knowing Lille until now. So my life here can be splited in two
	parts: before french and after french.
	</p>

	<p>
	Before french my week was more or less like this: I wake up (when I
	wake up... I&rsquo;m argentinian, which basically means I sleep late and
	wake up even later) then I go to office (a really nice building in a
	scientific park) and spend there... well, a lot of time. After that
	I can go to do some sport, or (more likely) go to down town for a
	beer or a wine with some of the team, usually <a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr">Nico</a>, <a href="http://marcusdenker.de/">Marcus</a>, Martin,
	<a href="https://twitter.com/camillobruni">Camillo</a> and <a href="http://benjamin.vanryseghem.com/">Ben</a> (time to time others join, but we are the
	&ldquo;regulars&rdquo;),we even have &ldquo;our place&rdquo;, a nice café (le café citoyen),
	very close to the main square.
	</p>

	<p>
	And well, after french... my life is more or less the same, but I
	interact a lot more with the locals, which are in general really nice
	people . And Lille as a city is very nice, with a great cultural
	life and even some cool night life (but again, as an argentinian I
	cannot certify that: things begin and end just to early for my
	regular tastes :)
	</p>

	<p>
	<b><i>What question would you ask another member of the team?</i></b>
	</p>

	<p>
	Do you want another beer?
	</p>


	<p>
	<b><i>Thank you Esteban!</i></b>
	</p>

	<p>
	If you liked this interview, you might also want to check out the
	<a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-damien.html">interview of Damien Cassou</a>.
	</p>

	<div id="disqus_thread"></div>
	<script type="text/javascript">
	/* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
	var disqus_shortname = 'nicolas-petton'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname

	/* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
	(function() {
	var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
	dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
	(document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
	})();
	</script>
	<noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
	<a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink">comments powered by <span class="logo-disqus">Disqus</span></a>
	]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
