<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
     xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
     xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel>
  <title>(Interview Företagsplatsen #2:  (bold (:begin 31 :end 42 :contents-begin 32 :contents-end 40 :post-blank 1 :parent #0) Benjamin) Van Ryseghem)</title>
  <atom:link href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-ben.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
  <language>en</language>
  <pubDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 17:27:44 +0100</pubDate>
  <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Feb 2015 17:27:44 +0100</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>Emacs 24.4 Org-mode 8.2.10</generator>
  <webMaster>nicolas@petton.fr (Nicolas Petton)</webMaster>
  <image>
    <url>http://nicolas-petton.fr/images/nicolas-petton.png</url>
    <title>(Interview Företagsplatsen #2:  (bold (:begin 31 :end 42 :contents-begin 32 :contents-end 40 :post-blank 1 :parent #0) Benjamin) Van Ryseghem)</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  </image>


  <item>
    <title>Interview with *Benjamin* Van Ryseghem</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-ben.html#sec-1</link>
    <author>Nicolas Petton</author>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-ben.html#sec-1</guid>
    <pubDate>Mon, 08 Dec 2014 17:38:00 +0100</pubDate>

    <description><![CDATA[
    <div class="pubdate">
    Dec 8, 2014
    </div>

    <p>
    Four months ago I moved to Stockholm, working full-time at
    <a href="http://foretagsplatsen.se/en">Företagsplatsen</a> as a software engineer. Företagsplatsen (or FTGP for
    short as we call it) is a really fun IT company to work at, I really
    enjoy the people and the culture. Just like I did with my previous
    job at Inria, I decided to do another series of interviews of my
    colleagues at FTGP.
    </p>

    <p>
    This is the second post of my series of interviews of my colleagues
    at <a href="http://foretagsplatsen.se">FTGP</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
    Ben joined FTGP almost a year ago. We previously worked together in
    the <a href="http://rmod.inria.fr">RMOD</a> team at Inria. We shared our office with <a href="http://damiencassou.seasidehosting.st">Damien</a> and the
    three of us had a lot of fun working together.
    </p>

    <p>
    Ben is a very close friend and a wonderful colleague, always joking
    around while always being ready to work. We do a lot of
    pair-programming sessions together, and often meet after work for a
    beer (those of you who know him know that I would be the one taking
    a beer, he would always take a coke), and do some coding evenings on
    free software <a href="http://www.teamwall.io/">projects</a> together.
    </p>


    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/ben-at-work.jpg" alt="Benjamin Van Ryseghem image" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 1:</span> Ben at work</p>
    </div>


    <p>
    <b><i>Hi Benjamin, thanks for taking this interview.
    First things first, could you tell me a bit about yourself?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    Really?
    </p>

    <p>
    Like we did not work together for the last 4 years? ;)
    </p>

    <p>
    So, I am Ben, 26yo, french and currently living in Stockholm for some months.
    I am a former Smalltalker, but nowadays more interested by Clojure/ClojureScript.
    </p>

    <p>
    At work I mainly work on the client part of our application done in Javascript.
    We are currently redoing the whole UI/UX and I really enjoy this :)
    </p>

    <p>
    I also spend quite a lot convincing Henrik (our CTO) to use more and
    more design patterns (like a lot ^^).
    </p>



    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/ben-laptop.jpg" alt="Ben's laptop image" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 2:</span> Ben&rsquo;s laptop</p>
    </div>


    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/ben-keyboard.jpg" alt="Ben's keyboard image" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 3:</span> Ben&rsquo;s keyboard</p>
    </div>

    <p>
    <b><i>Can you describe a typical work day at Företagsplatsen?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    I always start my day by emptying my email inbox (I am a &ldquo;0 email
    inbox” addict), and catching up what happened in the world, and in our
    codebase.
    </p>

    <p>
    I usually then spend 30 minutes to one hour to review the open pull
    requests (it goes with the “catching up” of what happened).
    </p>

    <p>
    Then depending on when I arrived at the office, either I pick a
    ticket and start working on it or I plan our 11am meeting. We have a
    daily meeting at 11am to plan the day, joke a lot and drink a
    coffee.  We try to have it short but it is usually around half an
    hour.
    </p>

    <p>
    We then work roughly half an hour and go to eat all together. These
    days, it’s between burgers and pizzas ;) It’s usually no longer than
    one hour.
    </p>

    <p>
    The afternoon is spent killing as many tickets as I can, often pair
    programming with others. Then I harass Henrik so he reviews my PRs
    (or “push the green button” as we call it :P)
    </p>

    <p>
    I try to end the day with a bit a &ldquo;relaxation coding” by coding a
    bit on my own projects.
    </p>

    <p>
    I think this sums it up :)
    </p>


    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/ben-fika.jpg" alt="fika" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 4:</span> A swedish fika</p>
    </div>

    <p>
    <b><i>What do you do on your free time? (both in front of and
    away from your computer)</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    In front of my computer, I like to experiment a lot.
    </p>

    <p>
    It explains why I have a lot of GitHub projects (most of them are
    just prototypes). Nowadays I am discovering Clojure and really like
    it.
    </p>

    <p>
    When I am away of my computer, I like to read (currently reading again
    LoTR), I am also a gamer (video games but also tabletop games).
    </p>

    <p>
    And when my brain is off, I watch series and movies (with a little
    preferences for grade-Z movies ^^).
    </p>

    <p>
    And for the days I am not afraid of natural light, I enjoy sharing a
    drink with friends.
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>In his <a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/interview-johan.html">interview</a>, Johan has a question for you:</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    Ben: I would like you to compare Sweden and France on the following
    5 questions (better or worse):
    </p>

    <ul class="org-ul">
    <li>Sweden is ...... than France at Ice hockey.
    </li>
    <li>Swedish hamburgers are ....... tasting than french ones.
    </li>
    <li>Swedish salaries are ....... than French ones.
    </li>
    <li>Swedish co-workers are ....... than French ones.
    </li>
    <li>Swedish girls are ....... looking than French ones.  
    </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
    Answer:
    </p>

    <ul class="org-ul">
    <li>Sweden is far more lame than France at Ice-hockey (I guess).
    </li>
    <li>Swedish hamburgers taste more or less the same that french ones.
    </li>
    <li>Swedish salaries are better than French ones (why would I be here
    for otherwise :P).
    </li>
    <li>Swedish co-workers are not as cool as French ones obviously.
    </li>
    <li>Swedish girls are generally better looking than French ones (as
    long as you do not tell that to my girlfriend :P).
    </li>
    </ul>

    <p>
    <b><i>If you were giving an interview, what question would you ask another member of the team?</i></b>
    </p>

    <p>
    What’s the biggest change since you had the (amazing/crazy) idea to hire two frenchies? ;)
    </p>

    <p>
    <b><i>Thank you Ben!</i></b>
    </p>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    <script type="text/javascript">
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'nicolas-petton'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
    var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
    dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
    (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
    </script>
    <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
    <a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink">comments powered by <span class="logo-disqus">Disqus</span></a>
    ]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
