<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
     xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
     xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel>
  <title>(No Smalltalk anymore)</title>
  <atom:link href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/no-more-smalltalk.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
  <language>en</language>
  <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 22:04:44 +0100</pubDate>
  <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jan 2015 22:04:44 +0100</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>Emacs 24.4 Org-mode 8.2.10</generator>
  <webMaster>nicolas@petton.fr (Nicolas Petton)</webMaster>
  <image>
    <url>http://nicolas-petton.fr/images/nicolas-petton.png</url>
    <title>(No Smalltalk anymore)</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  </image>


  <item>
    <title>No, I'm no doing any Smalltalk anymore</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/no-more-smalltalk.html#sec-1</link>
    <author>Nicolas Petton</author>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/no-more-smalltalk.html#sec-1</guid>
    <pubDate>Fri, 19 Dec 2014 12:29:00 +0100</pubDate>
    <category><![CDATA[amber]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[iliad]]></category>
    <category><![CDATA[smalltalk]]></category>
    <description><![CDATA[
    <div class="pubdate">
    December 19, 2014
    </div>

    <p>
    ... at least for now!
    </p>

    <p>
    Since I decided to step down as <a href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/amber-new-maintainer.html">Amber maintainer</a>, several colleagues
    and friends have asked me why I wasn&rsquo;t doing any Smalltalk anymore,
    some urging me to get back on track.
    </p>

    <p>
    It is true that I spent countless hours on <a href="http://amber-lang.net">Amber</a>, <a href="http://www.smalltalkhub.com">Smalltalkhub</a> and
    <a href="http://smalltalkhub.com/#!/~NicolasPetton/Iliad">Iliad</a> before that. Especially Amber, creating the language was one
    of the most exciting projects I had. Bootstrapping it from
    JavaScript then re-implementing everything in Amber itself was an
    awesome experience and I learned a lot in the process. I simply
    loved working on it.
    </p>

    <p>
    Smalltalk was the first language to really blow my mind. When I was
    a student and got introduced to Smalltalk, something happened. 
    </p>

    <p>
    So perhaps my decision to step down was sudden for some people, I
    can understand that. But like most things, it didn&rsquo;t happen in one
    day, it was rather an evolution and my job change was only the
    trigger. When I was working in <a href="http://rmod.inria.fr/">RMoD</a>, I was surrounded by
    Smalltalkers. The topic of the day was almost always related to
    Smalltalk in one way or another: of course I was doing (almost)
    everything in Smalltalk! And even before that, when I was working at
    Objectfusion, we were selling software entirely made in Smalltalk.
    </p>

    <p>
    I&rsquo;m now working in Sweden and my job is for the most part related to
    JavaScript. This means no more Smalltalk, at least at work.
    </p>

    <p>
    But to be fair, work is not the only reason, probably not even the
    main one. At a personal level, after many years, I think I got less
    interested in Smalltalk and wanted to learn new things and get more
    involved with other projects, one of them being <a href="https://www.gnu.org/software/emacs/">Emacs</a>.
    </p>

    <p>
    I might go back to Smalltalk, maybe sooner than I imagine, I don&rsquo;t
    know. In the meantime, Amber has a <a href="https://github.com/herby">new maintainer</a> who is making an
    awesome job, and Iliad is also maintained <a href="http://smalltalkhub.com/#!/~hernan/Iliad">on Smalltalkhub</a>.
    </p>
    ]]></description>
  </item>
</channel>
</rss>
