<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"
     xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
     xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
     xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
     xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
     xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
     xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
     xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
     xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
     xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/"><channel>
  <title>Going for a ThinkPad x220</title>
  <atom:link href="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/x220.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
  <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  <description><![CDATA[]]></description>
  <language>en</language>
  <pubDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 12:03:23 +0200</pubDate>
  <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Aug 2016 12:03:23 +0200</lastBuildDate>
  <generator>Emacs 25.1 Org-mode 8.3.5</generator>
  <webMaster>nicolas@petton.fr (Nicolas Petton)</webMaster>
  <image>
    <url>http://nicolas-petton.fr/images/nicolas-petton.png</url>
    <title>Going for a ThinkPad x220</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/</link>
  </image>


  <item>
    <title>Going for a ThinkPad x220</title>
    <link>http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/x220.html#orgheadline1</link>
    <author>nicolas@petton.fr (Nicolas Petton)</author>
    <guid isPermaLink="false">http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/x220.html#orgheadline1</guid>
    <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2016 23:45:00 +0200</pubDate>

    <description><![CDATA[<div class="pubdate">
    July 1, 2016
    </div>

    <div id="outline-container-orgheadline1" class="outline-3">
    <h3 id="orgheadline1"><a id="ID-4a2afa02-3144-419e-9f86-12d936c901f6"></a>Looking for the perfect secondary laptop</h3>
    <div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orgheadline1">
    <p>
    I've been looking for a second hand laptop to use at home and for travelling for
    a while, so that I wouldn't have to carry my primary laptop from and to work
    every day.
    </p>

    <p>
    I've been using a ThinkPad t440s for the last 2 years, and I'm really happy with
    it.  The keyboard - while being a chiclet keyboard - feels really good, the
    laptop is quite lightweight and slim for a 14 inches, and the IPS matte screen
    is amazing: it has very good viewing angles, a high resolution, and vibrant
    colors. However, I'm not happy at all with the trackpad, which lacks physical
    buttons, making the trackpoint pretty useless on this machine, a shame for a
    ThinkPad.
    </p>


    <div class="figure">
    <p><img src="http://nicolas-petton.fr/blog/../images/x220-keyboard.jpg" alt="x220 image" align="center" />
    </p>
    <p><span class="figure-number">Figure 1:</span> The keyboard of the ThinkPad x220</p>
    </div>
    </div>
    </div>

    <div id="outline-container-orgheadline1" class="outline-3">
    <h3 id="orgheadline1"><a id="ID-8b5b077c-383b-47d3-81ed-eca37673a017"></a>Going for a x220</h3>
    <div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orgheadline1">
    <p>
    After doing a bit of research, I decided to go for a refurbished ThinkPad
    x220. I found one in a local store in a very good shape, the laptop looks almost
    brand new, and it was pretty cheap (around 300€).
    </p>

    <p>
    It didn't have an IPS panel when I bought it, which is now a must for me, so I
    bought one on Ebay.  Same for the hard drive, I replaced it with an SSD.
    </p>
    </div>
    </div>

    <div id="outline-container-orgheadline1" class="outline-3">
    <h3 id="orgheadline1"><a id="ID-faa653cc-b6ae-4f27-a551-bc9392e128c9"></a>Review</h3>
    <div class="outline-text-3" id="text-orgheadline1">
    <p>
    I think the x220 is an amazing little machine!  
    </p>

    <p>
    It sure looks a bit oldish, but I don't mind that, I actually like its "good old
    ThinkPad" style, and the laptop feels very durable.
    </p>

    <p>
    I thought at first that a 12.5 inches display might be too small, but it's
    actually ok, and the IPS matte panel is of very good quality.
    </p>

    <p>
    The laptop is lightweight, small and easy to carry, even if it's a bit thick,
    which makes it the perfect travel companion.
    </p>

    <p>
    With a second generation Intel i7, 8Gb of RAM and a SSD, the machine is very
    responsive, actually almost as good as my t440s.
    </p>

    <p>
    The battery life is quite decent for a 5 years old computer: I got 4.5 hours
    with Fedora, doing Emacs hacking, with a browser open and a few terminals, using
    Wifi and with the screen brightness at 80%.  My x220 has the 6 cells battery, it
    still has about 80 percent of its original capacity, but I'm considering buying
    a brand new 9 cells battery to replace it.
    </p>

    <p>
    What is really amazing with this ThinkPad is the keyboard.  I thought that the
    keyboard on the t440s was very good, and well, the one on the x220 is so, so
    much better. It's not a chiclet keyboard, it's a full size keyboard, the key
    depth is very good and typing on it is a delight.
    </p>

    <p>
    All in all, I think I actually like the x220 better than the t440s. 
    </p>

    <p>
    Sure, it's a bit thicker than the t440s, but both weight about the same, and
    it's smaller, which means that it's easier to carry around.  Both have a good
    IPS matte display, with a better resolution for the t440s 14'' display, but the
    keyboard on the x220 is definitely superior.
    </p>

    <div id="disqus_thread"></div>
    <script type="text/javascript">
    /* * * CONFIGURATION VARIABLES: EDIT BEFORE PASTING INTO YOUR WEBPAGE * * */
    var disqus_shortname = 'nicolas-petton'; // required: replace example with your forum shortname

    /* * * DON'T EDIT BELOW THIS LINE * * */
    (function() {
    var dsq = document.createElement('script'); dsq.type = 'text/javascript'; dsq.async = true;
    dsq.src = '//' + disqus_shortname + '.disqus.com/embed.js';
    (document.getElementsByTagName('head')[0] || document.getElementsByTagName('body')[0]).appendChild(dsq);
    })();
    </script>
    <noscript>Please enable JavaScript to view the <a href="http://disqus.com/?ref_noscript">comments powered by Disqus.</a></noscript>
    <a href="http://disqus.com" class="dsq-brlink">comments powered by <span class="logo-disqus">Disqus</span></a>
    </div>
    </div>
    ]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
